Now we're going to talk about fish and if you lose one.
Unfortunately as I was doing a water change on my tank, I noticed one of my gold dust mollies has passed away.
When you lose a fish, make sure that you remove the fish properly.
If you don't, it can leave an unsightly mess in the tank and the other fish like to scavenge on dead fish.
Of course this is what they do in the wild.
Some people who get lazy such as myself sometimes we always don't remove the fish and the fish take care of it.
But for your purpose, I'm going to teach you the proper way to remove a dead fish.
Lift the lid on your tank.
You're going to use a nice little handy dandy tool which is called a fishnet which you use to remove the dead fish.
What I want to do is look in the front of the tank and see if I can't find the fish that has passed away.
For locating him in the tank, I'm going to use my net to find the fish, scoop him out and remove him out of the tank.
Once you remove the dead fish which we have in the tank, out of the fish tank, properly dispose of it in the commode.
So, if you send the fish out to big water, blue open sea where it can break down naturally.
Once you do this, your tank is happy and healthy.
And on an ending note if taking care of your tank, make sure you look at your fish tank everyday not only when you're feeding your fish but just to makes sure that you haven't lost any.
If you have any fish that are being too aggressive that you remove him from the tank so that they're not picking everybody else and pushing everybody up into one corner.
Sometimes this happens even on fish that are listed as a community fish.
Sometimes, they can get a little feisty and like to pick on other people in the tank.
Just like us, fish have personalities just like we do.
When you're a professionally person such as myself and if you don't mind touching a dead fish body, you can just put your hand in the tank, remove the dead fish and put it in a commode.
Just make sure you wash your hands thoroughly.
Another suggestion is we have Oscar fish which can get up to two feet in length, please do not put this on your commode.
A two foot fish which is two feet long, approximately a foot high and at two inches thick is not going to fit down a commode properly.
So, please put this big fish in a trash bag, seal the trash bag and put it in the trash can for proper disposable.
There, again, don't put the big fish in a commode.
Let alone a three foot algae eater 'cause it's just not going to fit.
Thanks again for coming to my house and letting me teach you on how to take care of a fish tank properly.